Mss.Rec.169 Mss.Rec.169
American Philosophical Society
Interviews with Comox Indians
1991
Mss.Rec.169
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings of the Comox or Silammon language. Contains numerous linguistic elicitation sessions for adjectives, verbs, miscelleanous expressions, animals, plants, insects, berries, clothing, trees, sea life, natural phenomena, household items, parts of the body, names of winds, and fishing-related vocabulary. Recorded at Powell River, British Columbia, by Honore Watanabe from July to October 1991.
4 sound cassettes (5 hr., 27 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Dominick, Annie
Dominick, Dave
George, Mary
Vivier, Margaret
Watanabe, Honore
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Honore Watanabe in 1992 (Acc. 1992-69r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Accompanying manuscript material is available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Comox Indians; Comox language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Elicitation of words for animals, berries, and fish, 1991-07-22; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:01; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Anthropological linguistics; Comox language; Powell River (B.C.)
  - Elicitation of words for plants and fish, 1991-07-24; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:24; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for fish, sea mammals, other native peoples, trees, seasons, and birds, 1991-07-26; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:30; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for miscellaneous animals and objects, 1991-07-28; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:57; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of numbers and names of winds, 1991-07-29; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:02; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for baskets and basket-making, 1991-07-30; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:39; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-07-31; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:53; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-08-01; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:57; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for miscellaneous material objects, 1991-08-12; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:10; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for natural phenomena, trees, animals, and sea life, 1991-08-21; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:08; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for insects, clothing, and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-08-22; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:08; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of verb forms and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-08-23; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:36; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Scope and Contents note
    Elicitation of verb forms for "wake up," "listen," "hear," and "talk," as well as miscellaneous vocabulary.
  - Elicitation of words for clothing and verbs, 1991-08-26; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:13; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of words for different kinds of clothing along with elicitation of verb forms for "go," "come," "respect," "steal," "run," and "chase."
  - Elicitation of words for parts of houses and miscelleneous vocabulary, 1991-08-27; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:43; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for physical conditions and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-08-29; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:33; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for household objects and the Story of the Bogeyman, 1991-08-30; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:42; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    The Story of the Bogeyman, given in Comox only, runs from 5:57 to 9:04.
    Anthropological linguistics; Comox Indians--Folklore; Comox language; Powell River (B.C.)
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous verbs, 1991-09-03; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:00; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of verb forms for "dirty," "clean," and "wash," with miscellaneous vocabulary.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary and expressions, 1991-09-04; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:39; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for parts of the body, 1991-09-05; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:06; Vivier, Margaret; Watanabe, Honoré
    Anthropological linguistics; Comox language; Human body--Terminology; Powell River (B.C.)
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous expressions, 1991-09-10; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:21; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary and expressions, 1991-09-11; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:32; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for household objects and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-17; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:11; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-18; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:21; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of fishing-related vocabulary and miscellaneous verbs, 1991-09-19; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:56; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of fishing-related nouns and expressions, along with verb forms for "show," "drink," and "laugh."
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-20; 03-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:24; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of words for animals and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-23; 03-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:29; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-24; 03-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:39; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of adjectives, 1991-09-25; 03-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:34; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of adjectives and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-26; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:55; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-27; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:32; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of verb forms of "help," "lie," "cut," "pull," "push," and "sit."
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-28; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:36; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of terms for fingers, verb forms for ""sprinkle," "stand," "sneak up," "step," "break," and miscellaneous vocabulary.
  - Elicitation of words for parts of the body and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-29; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:49; Dominick, Annie; Dominick, Dave; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of names of animals, 1991-09-30; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:56; Dominick, Dave; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-09-30; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:58; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of verbs and miscellaneous vocabulary, 1991-10-01; 04-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:27; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
  - Elicitation of verbs, 1991-10-02; 04-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:48; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré
    Elicitation of verb forms for "cut," "bite," "heal," "drop," "feed," and "hold," with miscellaneous vocabulary.
  - Elicitation of terms related to fish, verb forms, and inside/outside, 1991-10-03; 04-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:03; George, Mary; Watanabe, Honoré